Personal Info

7431 Allen Pines

281-857-1351

joshua@twinb0rnsoft.com

1995-05-11

https://github.com/ReckoningHero

http://www.twinb0rnsoft.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuanguyen soft1995/

Skills

C++, C# ,.NET Development, Java, and Python (Application Development)



Proficient coding and chosen IDE such as Visual Studio (ASP.NET), Dev C++, and MonoDevelop

Unreal Engine 4, Unity, 3D Max/Maya (Game Development and 3D Modeling)



Proficient

Jekyll , JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3 (Web

Development)



Testing Software





Joshua Nguyen

Software Tester |Future Software Developer| CS Student

I am a learner of all things software from inside and out. I have been a active programmer since the age of 15. Even since, I dive myself into a world of informations and algorithms that entice my passion to continue the pathway as a programmer. First programming language was Java, then it was C++. C++ thrives my enthusiasm with many IDE and SDK software such as game development and software in day to day basis needs. I specialized in game development such as Unity/ Unreal Engine 4 and .NET devlopment for desktop apps and sometimes websites. I am right now currently learning VR development so I can kickstart my career as maybe a future indie game developer. Even to this day, I am still learning each and every day to learn more about software implematation and how real world development works as time passes since learning my first code, "Hello World"!

Experience

2019-03 - Linguistic/Software Tester

present Welocalize

- Testing and debugging applications/websites for functional, linguistic, and problematic issues.
- Provided suggested solutions on linguistic issues and voice recognition software for client in tech.
- Provided Documents to account managers for reevaluation and direction needed.
- Work on several iOS devices to give to some engineers across the country to test the software and implement it better.

2018-10 - Web Developer Intern

2018-11 Fruition Technology Labs

- Build a home page website using the latest web technology such as HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Collaborate with other non-programmers and marketing team to get customers to attract to our website.

2017-09 - **Software Developer Intern**

2017-12 White Code Labs

- Programming C# .NET Projects and Apps for clients' needed expectations
- Perform software testing in case of debugging and errors.
- Using the latest software tools such as Docker and Visual Studios 2016 to maintain containers to clients and compile unique software.
- Assist and self-reliant in performing tasks and learning new soft skills on the job.

Education

2019-01 - Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, University of Houston Victoria, in at Katy Campus

Katy, Texas, Computer Science, 3.0 GPA

• Currently in courses with two semesters left before graduation in the Fall of 2019.

2016-01 - Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, University of Houston

Houston, Texas, Computer Science, 3.0 GPA

- Left because of high cost of tuition rate and courses not transferred correctly and accordingly to what I initially thought.
- Also left because of the Natural Science College was telling me that I should take another major since I somehow can't take the upper-level CS courses anymore due to "lack of prerequisites".

• Portfolio

Arduino Unity Project:

Objective: Educate users to learn the basics of Arduino in a short span of time with Unity3D. • TEAM PROJECT: Credit for First person mechanism and Room scene(Physics, Tables, and player's movement)

URL: http://www.twinb0rnsoft.com/Portfolio/

DirectX 2D Project: X Marks the Spot

Objective: •Present a possible framework that can entice to a game environment without game editor. • Asserting and building the C++ framework from scratch using the latest DirectX 11 dependencies and files. 2D DirectX game initialing the user to obtain the goal up to 20 times

URL: https://github.com/ReckoningHero/X-Marks-the-Spot